All self-driving cars go through
所有无人驾驶车都需要经过
the same series of steps to safely navigate through the world.
相同步骤 才能安全地畅游世界
You've been working on the first step, localization.
我们之前一直在学习第一步 定位
Before cars can safely navigate,
在汽车安全行驶之前
they first use sensors and
它们首先使用传感器和
other collected data to best estimate where they are in the world.
其他收集的数据 以最佳地估计在世界中的位置
In this lesson, we'll be talking about representing and predicting car movement.
本节课中 我们将学习如何表示和预测汽车运动
But before we do, let's review all the steps
不过首先 让我们来看看
that a common filter takes to localize a car.
普通滤波器要定位一辆汽车的所有步骤
First, we start with an initial prediction of
首先 我们先初步预测
our cars location and
汽车位置和
the probability distribution that describes our uncertainty about that prediction.
能描述这种预测不确定性的概率分布
Here's a one-dimensional example in which we know that our car
这是一个一维例子 我们知道汽车
is on this one lane road but we don't know its exact location.
在这条单车道上 但不知道它的确切位置
And so, our prior probability distribution is uniform.
因此 我们的先验概率分布是均匀的
We then sense the world around the car.
然后我们来感知汽车周围的世界
This is called the measurement update step in which we gather
这就是测量更新步骤 通过这种步骤
more information about the car's surroundings and refine our location prediction.
我们可以收集更多关于汽车周边环境的信息 并改进我们的位置预测
Say we measure that we're about two grid cells in front of the stop sign.
假设测量结果是 我们大概位于停车标志前面的两个网格单元格
Our measurement isn't perfect but we have a much better idea of our car's location.
虽然这种测量并不完美 但我们对于汽车的位置有了更好的了解
The next step is moving,
下一步是移动
also called the time update or prediction step.
也称为时间更新或预测步骤
We predict where the car will move based on the knowledge we have about its velocity and
根据我们对其速度和当前位置的了解 我们预测汽车将在哪里移动
current position and we shift our probability distribution to reflect this movement.
我们改变概率分布来反映这一运动
This example shows a one-cell movement to the right and
这个示例显示了向右边移动一个单元格的运动
this gives us a new state estimate for the position of the car.
这为我们提供了一个关于汽车位置的新的状态估计
The Kalman Filter simply repeats the sense and move
卡尔曼滤波器只是重复检测和移动测量
measurement and prediction steps to localize the car as it's moving.
和预测步骤 从而在汽车运动时定位汽车
The beauty of Kalman Filters is that they combine
卡尔曼滤波器的优点是
somewhat inaccurate sensor measurements with somewhat inaccurate predictions of motion to
将有些不准确的传感器测量和同样的运动预测结合起来
get a filtered location estimate that's better than any estimates that
通过筛选 得到一个比任何估计值更好的位置估计值
come from only sensor readings or only knowledge about movement.
这是仅靠传感器读数或对汽车运动的了解所做不到的
This is why a common filter is such a powerful localization method.
这就是普通滤波器在定位方面如何有效的原因